BU Records: BaylorFans.com Discussion Board, Inclusive: 2001-2008, Bulk: 2004-2008
Baylor University Libraries
BU Records: BaylorFans.com Discussion Board
Inclusive: 2001-2008, Bulk: 2004-2008
Baylor University Libraries https://www.baylor.edu/library/
BU/404
BaylorFans.com, 1999 - 2016
10 document boxes
BU Records: BaylorFans.com contains message board posts discussing a wide variety of topics related to Baylor and its administration, with a focus on President Robert Sloan’s administration and the Baylor 2012 initiative.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
BaylorFans.com come was started by Jason Stewart in 1999 as an independent website aimed at fans of Baylor Athletics. The website was incorporated as a limited liability corporation on 2000 August 9, listing Stewart as the president. By 2001, the website included a message board with forums for “Baylor Sports” as well as the “Baylor Community.” In the summer of 2017, BaylorFans.com was acquired by and merged with SicEm365. As of 2021 March 4, the URL “baylorfans.com” redirects to “SicEm365.com.”
Scope and Content
BU Records: BaylorFans.com consists of materials from 2001-2008. The materials are arranged in a single series entitled “Discussion Board Posts.” The documents reflect the posts of registered users of BaylorFans.com. Most of the posts are from the “Religion and Politics” subforum, which was part of the “Baylor Community” section of the message board.
The posts discuss a variety of topics related to Baylor and its administration during the final years of Robert Sloan’s presidency and the short term of John Lilley’s presidency. Some frequently recurring topics include Robert Sloan’s administration, the Baylor 2012 initiative, the relationship between faculty and the administration, the role of Baptist Christianity at Baylor, and Baylor’s finances. Posters frequently copied articles from newspapersDLthe Waco Tribune-Herald is a favorite sourceDLand other publications in order to spark discussion. The posters also use obscure acronyms in their discussions. “FOB” stands for the “Friends of Baylor” organization, whose express purpose was to improve Baylor’s public image. “CRIB” stands for the “Committee to Restore Integrity to Baylor,” an organization formed to expose and correct perceived faults in Robert Sloan’s administration.
Although the collection is generally in good condition, some items have the right edge of the text cut off. The reason for this printing error appears to be that the width of the webpages was wider than the width of the printable area on the physical pages. This printing error happens most often with posts printed in color.
Arrangement
The collection showed signs of previous, albeit incomplete, processing. Items were arranged in folders and placed in document boxes. Folders were labelled according to the topics of their contents and arranged alphabetically. However, that arrangement was inconsistent, with the final two boxes containing several folders that were not in alphabetical sequence and some folder titles not accurately reflecting their contents.
Folders were reordered to make the alphabetical arrangement consistent. Some folders were renamed in order to add clarity. For example, “2012” was renamed “Baylor 2012” to clarify that the contents referred specifically to Baylor University’s 10-year initiative rather than the year. Other folders were renamed to reflect their contents more accurately. For example, the collection originally contained five folders titled “Playboy.” Only half of the items in the first folder were related to the folder title. The other items in the first folder were placed in a folder titled “Finances.” The second and third Playboy folders were similarly renamed “Finances.” The remaining two Playboy folders were renamed “Presidential Search.” Folders titled “Homecoming” and “Religion” were renamed “Homosexuality” and “Tier 1 University,” respectively. Errors and misspellings in folder titles were also corrected. Personal information was redacted.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/404.
Related Resources
Related references
“Franchise Tax Account Status: BaylorFans.Com, LLC, Tax ID 32002664731.” Texas Comptroller of Public Accounts. Accessed 2021 March 4.
“Message Boards.” BaylorFans.com. 2001 December 5. Internet Archive. Accessed 2021 March 4.
SimEm365 Staff. “Welcome to Sicem365.com.” SicEm365, 2017 November 1. Accessed 2021 March 4.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Sloan, Robert Bryan, 1949-
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Administration.; Baylor University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Baylor University -- Endowments.; Baylor University -- Faculty Senate.; Baylor University -- Faculty.; Baylor University -- Finance.; Baylor University -- Presidents.
Subjects
Baptist universities and colleges -- Texas -- Waco -- Finance.; Baptist universities and colleges -- Texas -- Waco.
- Discussion Board Posts, 2001-2008; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains printouts of message board posts discussing a variety of topics about Baylor University and its administration. The series is in good condition.
  - Accreditation, 2004 June 14-December 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administration (1 of 2), 2004 December 17-2007 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administration (2 of 2), 2006 June 27-August 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Admissions, 2005 January 31-2008 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aggies in Waco, 2004 April 12-October 20 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alumni, 2006 May 7-2008 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Association (1 of 2), 2004 June 18-2008 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Association (2 of 2), 2007 February 2-October 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Athletics, 2006 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Aviation Institute, 2004 March 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Baylor 2012 (1 of 3), 2006 January 5-2008 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Baylor 2012 (2 of 3), 2004 March 17-2007 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Baylor 2012 (3 of 3), 2002 November 29-2005 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baylor Publications, 2004 March 2-2007 November 8 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Baylor Truth Blog, 2004 October 23-December 23 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Board of Regents (1 of 4), 2007 April 29-2008 June 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Board of Regents (2 of 4), 2004 June 12-2008 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Board of Regents (3 of 4), 2003 May 17-2004 August 4 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Board of Regents (4 of 4), 2003 May 17-2006 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brooks, 2006 February 4-April 27 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Buildings, 2006 January 27-2008 April 21 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chapel, 2006 April 22-2007 October 23 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - ChurchDLState Studies, 2006 February 15-June 16 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Commencement, 2006 May 17-2007 October 23 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Committee to Restore Integrity to Baylor, 2004 May 26-2005 February 21 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Communications Department, 2004 March 6-July 26 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum, 2004 December 16-23 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Davis, Will, 2005 January 16-June 9 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Debate Team, 2006 May 1-2007 October 23 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Enrollment, 2004 April 12-2005 July 28 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Faculty General (1 of 4), 2008 March 21-June 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Faculty General (2 of 4), 2006 May 19-2008 June 27 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Faculty General (3 of 4), 2006 January 22-2008 June 2 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Faculty General (4 of 4), 2004 April 12-2008 August 5 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Faculty Hiring, 2004 July 3-2005 July 27 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Faculty Referendum (1 of 4), 2004 December 7-23 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Referendum (2 of 4), 2004 November 30-December 7 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Referendum (3 of 4), 2004 December 2-7 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Referendum (4 of 4), 2004 December 2-7 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Senate, 2004 March 4-20 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Faculty/Staff Relationship (1 of 2), 2004 March 1-2005 January 11 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Faculty/Staff Relationship (2 of 2), 2004 March 26-2005 June 9 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Faith and Learning, 2004 October 28-2006 January 19 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Finances (1 of 3), 2004 June 15-2007 September 27 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Finances (2 of 3), 2006 February 8-2008 August 22 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Finances (3 of 3), 2004 March 1-2007 November 19 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Friends of Baylor, 2005 February 17-2007 October 23 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fundamentalism, 2004 December 2-23 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - General (1 of 7), 2006 May 5-2007 November 9 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - General (2 of 7), 2006 May 5-2008 June 5 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - General (3 of 7), 2005 September 24-2008 August 29 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - General (4 of 7), 2004 November 4-2008 January 18 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - General (5 of 7), 2004 June 23-2006 June 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - General (6 of 7), 2004 June 26-2006 August 18 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General (7 of 7), 2004 December 5-2005 July 18 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - George Bush Library, 2004 December 28-2008 February 29 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Gilbreath, Kent, 2004 November 30-December 7 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Gregory, Joel, 2005 July 29-August 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - History Department, 2004 March 11-20 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Homosexuality, 2004 March 1-2005 December 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Institutes/Initiatives, 2005 May 5-2008 January 18 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Jeffrey, David Lyle (1 of 2), 2004 March 30-2005 June 9 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Jeffrey, David Lyle (2 of 2), 2004 April 14-2006 July 7 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Law School, 2004 March 18—2008 February 13 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Lectures, 2006 June 12-2007 November 9 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Lilley, John (1 of 6), 2006 March 29-2008 August 7 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Lilley, John (2 of 6), 2006 January 3-2008 September 3 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Lilley, John (3 of 6), 2007 August 11-2008 June 5 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Lilley, John (4 of 6), 2008 April 21-24 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Lilley, John (5 of 6), 2001 August-2006 April 20 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Lilley, John (6 of 6), 2005 November 4-2008 July 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - McCall, Abner, 2004 June 21-July 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - McCall, Dick, 2004 June 14 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Playboy, 2006 April 23-2007 October 23 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Presidential Search (1 of 2), 2004 June 14-2008 September 10 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Presidential Search (2 of 2), 2008 May 13-September 15 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Provost Office, 2005 June 2-2007 October 23 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Racism, 2006 April 7-2008 December 5 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Rankings, 2004 April 11-14 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Religion, 2005 January 23 —2006 February 23 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Research, 2007 July 25-2008 August 22 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Reynolds, 2002 October 21-2005 February 21 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Robinson, 2004 September 4 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - School of Business, 2005 July 21-2006-June 6 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - School of Education, 2004 April 6-14 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Separation of Church and State, 2006 August 28-31 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Sloan, Robert (1 of 14), 2004 June 17-August 4 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Sloan, Robert (2 of 14), 2000 July 24-2005 July 14 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Sloan, Robert (3 of 14), 2004 November 21-2005 January 3 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sloan, Robert (4 of 14), 2004 March 2-December 13 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Sloan, Robert (5 of 14), 2004 June 14-October 14 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Sloan, Robert (6 of 14), 2004 April 9-2005 June 14 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Sloan, Robert (7 of 14), 2004 April 11-2005 July 14 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Sloan, Robert (8 of 14), 2004 June 21-2005 February 7 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Sloan, Robert (9 of 14), 2004 March 12—2006 August 24 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Sloan, Robert (10 of 14), 2004 June 7-2007 September 27 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Sloan, Robert (11 of 14), 2004 December 13-2007 September 20 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Sloan, Robert (12 of 14), 2004 April 6-2008 April 14 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Sloan, Robert (13 of 14), 2004 October 19-2006 August 18 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Sloan, Robert (14 of 14), 2004 June 14-2008 July 11 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Telecommunications, 2004 March 13-2005 July 14 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Tenure, 2005 January 25-2008 June 16 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Tier 1 University, 2004 December 22-2005 June 9 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Toben, Brad, 2008 July 28-August 6 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Traditions, 2007 November 2-2008 April 18 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Truett Seminary, 2008 August 8-22 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Tuition/Financial Aid (1 of 4), 2004 October 24-2007 October 2 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Tuition/Financial Aid (2 of 4), 2004 October 21-2006 June 23 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Tuition/Financial Aid (3 of 4), 2006 April 11-2007 November 19 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Tuition/Financial Aid (4 of 4), 2006 June 24-2007 November 19 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Underwood, Bill (1 of 3), 2005 April 29-2006 December 5 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Underwood, Bill (2 of 3), 2005 May 3-December 5 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Underwood, Bill (3 of 3), 2005 June 2-August 18 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Wood, Ralph, 2005 June 29-July14 (Box 10, Folder 8)